Over time, it is highly likely that
you will generate quite a lot of
files and folders on your computer.
For most modern  computers,  this isn't
an issue as you have high capacity disk
drives, cloud storage or high capacity
removable media where files can be stored.
However, there may still be instances
where you wish to compress files.
This could be for archiving into a limited
space, or it may be that you need to send
some files as an attachment to an email
and compressing them will reduce the
size of the file that needs to be sent.
So, to compress a folder, I'm going
to demonstrate with the ITQ folder.
So I'll highlight the ITQ folder
and simply select the cog icon
and then select compress ITQ.
This then is creating a zip file, as
you can see, indicated with the folder
with the zip  the center of the icon.
So once that's done, I'll just
quickly move that there and that
has then compressed that folder.
So just to see how much
it has compressed it by.
I can highlight the ITQ folder
and select Get Info, which will
then give me the information.
So that is 1.8 megabytes in size.
So the original size was that, and again,
I can highlight the zip file and select
Get Info and that will then give me
the information on that, which is 1.5
megabytes, which may not seem much, but if
you bear in mind that you could have quite
a lot of files and a lot of folders within
there it can save quite a bit of space.